My name is Amit.
اسمي هو أميت.
And 18 months ago, I had another job at Google,
وقبل 18 شهرا، كنت أشغل وظيفة أخرى في غوغل،
and I pitched this idea
رميت بفكرة
of doing something with museums and art
القيام بأمر بخصوص الفن والمتاحف
to my boss who's actually here,
إلى رئيستي في العمل والتي توجد في الواقع هنا،
and she allowed me to do it.
وسمحت لي بالقيام بذلك.
And it took 18 months.
وقد استغرقني الأمر 18 شهرا.
A lot of fun, negotiations and stories, I can tell you,
الكثير من المفاوضات والقصص الممتعة، يمكنني اخباركم بها،
with 17 very interesting museums from nine countries.
مع 17 متحفا مثيرا للإهتمام من تسع دول.
But I'm going to focus on the demo.
لكنني سأركز على الاستعراض.
There are a lot of stories about why we did this.
هناك الكثير من القصص حول لماذا قمنا بهذا.
I think my personal story is explained very simply on the slide,
أعتقد أن قصتي الشخصية موضحة بشكل مبسط على الشريحة،
and it's access.
وهي الوصول.
And I grew up in India.
وقد نشأت في الهند.
I had a great education -- I'm not complaining --
حصلت على تعليم جيد -- لست أشتكي --
but I didn't have access to a lot of these museums and these artworks.
لكنني لم أستطع الوصول إلى الكثير من المتاحف والأعمال الفنية.
And so when I started traveling and going to these museums,
وبالتالي حين بدأت أسافر وأذهب إلى هذه المتاحف،
I started learning a lot.
بدأت في تعلم الكثير.
And while working at Google,
وخلال العمل في غوغل،
I tried to put this desire
أحاول وضع هذه الرغبة
to make it more accessible with technology together.
لزيادة قابلية الوصول إليه مع التكنولوجيا معا.
So we formed a team, a great team of people,
وهكذا كوننا فريقا، فريقا عظيما من الناس،
and we started doing this.
وبدأنا في القيام بهذا.
I'm going to probably get into the demo
سأقوم على الأرجح ببدء الإستعراض
and then tell you a couple of the interesting things
ثم اخباركم ببعض الأمور المهمة
we've had since launch.
التي تعرضنا لها منذ الانطلاق.
So, simple: you come to GoogleArtProject.com.
إذن ببساطة: تأتي إلى GoogleArtProject.com.
You look around at all these museums here.
تنظر حولك إلى هذه المتاحف هنا.
You've got the Uffizi, you've got the MoMA,
لدينا Uffizi، لدينا MoMA،
the Hermitage, the Rijks, the Van Gogh.
الـ Hermitage، الـRijks، الـ Van Gogh.
I'm going to actually get to one of my favorites,
سأقوم بالفعل بزيارة أحد مفضلاتي،
the Metropolitan Museum of Art in New York.
متحف المتروبوليتان للفنون في نيويورك.
Two ways of going in -- very simple.
طريقتان للدخول -- في غاية البساطة.
Click and, bang, you're in this museum.
انقر و، بانغ ها أنت داخل المتحف.
It doesn't matter where you are --
لا يهم أين أنت --
Bombay, Mexico, it doesn't really matter.
بومباي، المكسيك، لا يهم في الواقع.
You move around, you have fun.
تتنقل، تقضي وقتا ممتعا.
You want to navigate around the museum?
تريد التنقل حول المتحف؟
Open the plan up,
افتح الرسم التخطيطي،
and, in one click, jump.
وفي ضغطة واحدة، تقفز.
You're in there, you want to go to the end of the corridor.
أنت هناك، وتريد الذهاب إلى آخر الرواق.
Keep going. Have fun.
استمر في الذهاب، اقض وقتا ممتعا.
Explore.
استكشف.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thanks. I haven't come to the best part.
شكرا. لم أصل بعد إلى أحسن جزء.
(Laughter)
(ضحك)
So now I'm in front of one of my favorite paintings,
وهكذا أنا الآن أمام أحد اللوحات المفضلة لدي،
"The Harvesters" by Pieter Bruegel at the Met.
الحصادات للفنان بيتر بروغل في الميت.
I see this plus sign.
أرى إشارة زائد هنا.
If the museum has given us the image, you click on it.
إن وفر المتحف الصورة، تضغط عليها.
Now this is one of the images.
الآن هذه إحدى الصور.
So this is all of the meta-data information.
إذن هذه كل معلومات البينات الفوقية.
For those of you who are truly interested in art,
وللمهتمين منكم بالفنون حقا،
you can click this -- but I'm going to click this off right now.
يمكنكم الضغط على هذا -- لكنني سأضغط لإيقافه حاليا.
And this is one of these images that we captured
وهذه الصورة من بين الصور التي التقطناها
in what we call gigapixel technology.
فيما نسميه بتكنولوجيا الغيغابكسل.
So this image, for example,
ولذلك هذه الصورة، على سبيل المثال،
has close to, I think, around 10 billion pixels.
لديها ما يقارب، على ما أعتقد، حوالي 10 مليار بيكسل.
And I get a lot of people asking me:
والكثير من الناس يسألونني:
"What do you get for 10 billion pixels?"
"ما الذي تحصل عليه من 10 ملايير بيكسل؟"
So I'm going to try and show you what you really get for 10 billion pixels.
وبالتالي سأحاول عرض ما تحصل عليها فعلا من 10 ملايير بيكسل.
You can zoom around very simply.
يمكن التكبير بسهولة فائقة.
You see some fun stuff happening here.
ترى بعض الأمور الممتعة تحصل هنا.
I love this guy; his expression is priceless.
أحب هذا الرجل؛ تعبير وجهه لا يقدر بثمن.
But then you really want to go deep.
لكن نريد في الحقيقة أن نذهب عميقا.
And so I started playing around,
وبالتالي بدأت ألعب حواليها،
and I found something going on over here.
ووجدت أمرا يحصل هناك.
And I was like, "Hold on. That sounds interesting."
فقلت، "لحظة. يبدو هذا مثيرا للإهتمام."
Went in, and I started noticing
ذهبت داخلا، وبدأت ألاحظ
that these kids were actually beating something.
أن هؤلاء الأطفال كانوا في الواقع يضربون شيئا.
I did a little research, spoke to a couple of my contacts at the Met,
أجريت بعض البحوث، وتحدثت إلى بعض من معارفي في ميت،
and actually found out that this is a game
وقد وجدت أن هذه لعبة
called squall,
تسمى [غير واضح]،
which involves beating a goose with a stick
والتي تشمل ضرب إوزة بعصا
on Shrove Tuesday.
في ثلاثاء المرافع.
And apparently it was quite popular.
ويبدو أنها كانت مشهورة للغاية.
I don't know why they did it,
لا أعرف لماذا فعلوا ذلك،
but I learned something about it.
لكنني تعلمت شيئا بخصوصها.
Now just to get really deep in, you can really get to the cracks.
الآن وفقط للذهاب عميقا، يمكن فعلا الوصول إلى الشقوق.
Now just to give you some perspective,
الآن فقط لإعطائكم منظورا،
I'm going to zoom out so you really see what you get.
سأقوم بالتكبير، لترون بالفعل ما تحصلون عليه.
Here is where we were,
هنا حيث كنا،
and this is the painting.
وهذه هي اللوحة.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
The best is yet to come -- so in a second.
الأفضل سيأتي قريبا -- وبالتالي في ثانية.
So now let's just quickly
وبالتالي الآن دعونا فقط سريعا
jump into the MoMA, again in New York.
نفقز إلى متحف الفن الحديث، مجددا في نيويورك.
So another one of my favorites, "The Starry Night."
إذن أحد مفضلاتي، الليلة المضيئة بالنجوم.
Now the example I showed you was all about finding details.
الآن المثال الذي عرضته عليكم كان كله حول إيجاد التفاصيل.
But what if you want to see brush strokes?
لكن ماذا لو أردتم رؤية آثار الفرشاة؟
And what if you want to see
وماذا إن أردتم رؤية
how Van Gogh actually created this masterpiece?
كيف قام فان غوخ فعلا بإنتاج هذه التحفة؟
You zoom in. You really go in.
نقوم بالتكبير. ونذهب بالفعل داخلا.
I'm going to go to one of my favorite parts in this painting,
أنا ذاهب إلى إحدى الأجزاء المفضلة لدي في اللوحة،
and I'm really going to get to the cracks.
وسأقوم فعلا بالوصول إلى الشقوق.
This is "The Starry Night,"
هذه هي لوحة الليلة المضيئة بالنجوم،
I think, never seen like this before.
أعتقد أنكم لم تروا هذه من قبل.
I'm going to show you my other favorite feature.
سأريكم الخاصية الأخرى المفضلة لدي.
There's a lot of other stuff here, but I don't have time.
هناك الكثير من الأمور الأخرى هنا، لكن ليس لدي وقت كاف.
This is the real cool part. It's called Collections.
هذا هو الجزء الرائع فعلا. يدعى المجموعات.
Any one of you, anybody --
أي كان، أي واحد --
doesn't matter if you're rich, if you're poor,
لا يهم ما إذا كنت غنيا، أو فقيرا،
if you have a fancy house -- doesn't matter.
إن كان لديك منزل فاخر -- لا يهم.
You can go and create your own museum online --
يمكنكم المضي وإنشاء متحفكم الخاص على الأنترنيت --
create your own collection across all these images.
إنشاء مجموعة الخاصة من خلال كل الصور.
Very simply, you go in --
بكل بساطة، نذهب داخلا --
and I've created this, called The Power of Zoom --
وقد أنشأت هذه المسماة التكبير القوي --
you can just zoom around.
يمكن فقط التكبير حواليه.
This is "The Ambassadors," based in the National Gallery.
هذه هي لوحة السفراء، توجد في المعرض الوطني.
You can annotate the stuff, send it to your friends
يمكن تعليق أشياء، وإرسالها إلى أصدقائكم
and really get a conversation going
وبدء محادثة فعلية
about what you're feeling
حول ما تحس به
when you go through these masterpieces.
حين تنظر إلى هذه التحف.
So I think, in conclusion,
لذا أعتقد، باختصار،
for me, the main thing
بالنسبة لي، أهم شيء
is that all the amazing stuff here does not really come from Google.
هو أن كل الأمور الباهرة هنا لا تأتي في الواقع من غوغل.
It doesn't, in my opinion, even come from the museums.
لا تأتي، في اعتقادي، حتى من المتاحف.
I probably shouldn't say that.
ربما لا يجدر بي قول هذا.
It really comes from these artists.
إنها تأتي من الفنانين.
And that's been my humbling experience in this.
وهذه كانت تجربتي المتواضعة في هذا.
I mean, I hope in this digital medium
أقصد، أتوسم في هذه الوسيلة الرقمية
that we do justice to their artwork
أن تعيد الإعتبار لأعمالهم
and represent it properly online.
وتعرضها بشكل مناسب على الأنترنيت.
And the biggest question I get asked nowadays
وأكبر سؤال يطرح علي حاليا
is, "Did you do this
هو، "هل قمت بهذا
to replicate the experience of going to a museum?"
لإستنساخ تجربة الذهاب إلى المتحف؟"
And the answer is no.
والجواب هو لا.
It's to supplement the experience.
إنه لتكميل التجربة.
And that's it. Thank you.
هذا كل ما لدي. شكرا لكم.
(Applause)
(تصفيق)
Thank you.
شكرا لكم.